<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sroesch.de on sroesch.de</title>
    <link>https://sroesch.de/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sroesch.de on sroesch.de</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://sroesch.de/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Days of Code - Challenge accepted.</title>
      <link>https://sroesch.de/2020/100-days-of-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sroesch.de/2020/100-days-of-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last few months were very busy, since I had a large personal project going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I moved away from Stuttgart, back to the area I come from. In early autumn Theresa and I started to look for a suitable flat. We browsed the listings every day and had several viewings. In October we found the flat we were looking for and signed the contract. Now the next level started: coming up with a solution for all the &lt;del&gt;annoying&lt;/del&gt; lovely quirks of the old building, and planning when and how to move in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This and the excecution of our plans took way more of our time than we expected. But around two weeks ago we finally reached the point were we were happy with what we have so far and decided that we are &amp;ldquo;done&amp;rdquo; with moving in. We also had some friends and family coming over to celebrate this and to say thanks to all the people that helped us. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why am I writing this in an artivle tha is about a code challenge? There are two reasons. The first is, that the relocation process forced me reduce the time I put into coding projects (and other things..). The challenge is kind of a restart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second reason is, that the new home gave me lots of ideas for small projects I want to to in the future. Some of them &lt;del&gt;might&lt;/del&gt; will find there way on this blog soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I´ll start the #100DaysOfCode challenge. The challenge is trending on twitter currently and there is even an official website: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.100daysofcode.com/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.100daysofcode.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magic Mirror</title>
      <link>https://sroesch.de/2019/magic-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sroesch.de/2019/magic-mirror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some years ago, I stumbled upon the blog of a dutch guy, that had a great &lt;a href=&#34;https://michaelteeuw.nl/post/80391333672/magic-mirror-part-i-the-idea-the-mirror&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;idea&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not make a ordinary mirror more useful by displaying additional, helpful information on the surface of the mirror?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how, you ask? Michael (the dutch guy) came up with a very smart solution. He stripped down an old monitor and placed it behind a semi-transparent mirror (like the mirrors in a police interrogation room). Add a wooden frame and a Rasperry Pi that fills the screen with content and there you go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://sroesch.de/images/2019/6/explode.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Magic Mirror explode sketch.&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael did&amp;rsquo;t stop there. He created a fullblown open source software called &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MichMich/MagicMirror/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MagicMirror&lt;/a&gt;, that allows you to display all sorts of information (calendar, weather, news, train schedule, etc.). In addition to the build-in modules, MagicMorror provides a powerful add-on mechnism and offers plenty of custom addons, thanks to the fantastic &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.magicmirror.builders/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;community&lt;/a&gt; that emerged around Michael&amp;rsquo;s software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was fascinated by the idea to display useful information in an unobstrusive and delighting way. Ideally delighting enough, to get an acceptable WAF. After reading about another &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@maxbraun/my-bathroom-mirror-is-smarter-than-yours-94b21c6671ba&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mirror project&lt;/a&gt; - this time implemented by Max Braun, an engnieer a Google - I was conviced, that this is possible and started to work own my own mirror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mirror is based on the MagicMirror software and the following hardware:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi 3B&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asus MB169B+ - a ultra-slim USB-monitor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.5m * 0.4m * 0,3cm mirror glass - I ordered it &lt;a href=&#34;https://forum.magicmirror.builders/topic/1011/order-closed-two-way-mirror-order-in-germany/3?page=1&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IKEA Ribba frame, 0.5m * 0.4m - I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the tools to build my own frame, this was a great and inexpensive alternative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PIR sensor - used to turn on the screen once movement is detected near the mirror&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5.8GHZ Microwave Radar Sensor - I replaced the PIR with this, since this one can be placed behind the glass of the mirror&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll update this post with more info about my build, such as the modules I use and some pictures of the result.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello internet. It´s me, Sebastian.</title>
      <link>https://sroesch.de/2019/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sroesch.de/2019/welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, a few weeks ago I decided to create my personal blog. Nothing fancy, mostly just a place to share the things I do in my nerd time. Conveniently creating this blog is in itself one of the nerdy things I can write about. But I´ll safe that for another day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is meant to introduce myself.
I´m a 31-year-old guy born near Freiburg and living in Stuttgart. I like doing and watching sports, hanging out with friends and family, cooking and reading &lt;del&gt;books&lt;/del&gt; on my kindle. Between weekends I work as a software engineer for one of the two car companies in this town.
I´m a very curious type of guy. I like to dip my toe in new concepts and technologies - be it hardware or software - with a focus on unobstrusive solutions that still upgrade some inconvenient thing in my everyday life.
Examples: discreet home automation, a smart mirror or a more beautiful shell for one of my Sonos speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, as I said initially: nothing fancy. But maybe still interesting for some of you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sebastian&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About sroesch.de</title>
      <link>https://sroesch.de/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sroesch.de/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
