<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on sroesch.de</title>
    <link>https://sroesch.de/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on sroesch.de</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sroesch.de/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>100 Days of Code - Challenge accepted.</title>
      <link>https://sroesch.de/2020/100-days-of-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sroesch.de/2020/100-days-of-code/</guid>
      <description>The last few months were very busy, since I had a large personal project going on.
I moved away from Stuttgart, back to the area I come from. In early autumn Theresa and I started to look for a suitable flat. We browsed the listings every day and had several viewings. In October we found the flat we were looking for and signed the contract. Now the next level started: coming up with a solution for all the annoying lovely quirks of the old building, and planning when and how to move in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magic Mirror</title>
      <link>https://sroesch.de/2019/magic-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sroesch.de/2019/magic-mirror/</guid>
      <description>Some years ago, I stumbled upon the blog of a dutch guy, that had a great idea:
 Why not make a ordinary mirror more useful by displaying additional, helpful information on the surface of the mirror?
 But how, you ask? Michael (the dutch guy) came up with a very smart solution. He stripped down an old monitor and placed it behind a semi-transparent mirror (like the mirrors in a police interrogation room).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello internet. It´s me, Sebastian.</title>
      <link>https://sroesch.de/2019/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sroesch.de/2019/welcome/</guid>
      <description>So, a few weeks ago I decided to create my personal blog. Nothing fancy, mostly just a place to share the things I do in my nerd time. Conveniently creating this blog is in itself one of the nerdy things I can write about. But I´ll safe that for another day.
This post is meant to introduce myself. I´m a 31-year-old guy born near Freiburg and living in Stuttgart. I like doing and watching sports, hanging out with friends and family, cooking and reading books on my kindle.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>